Guide to the Virginia Gardner Papers TAM.100
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series IV: Journalism Career, 61084
  - Subseries IV:E: New York employment, 61085
    - Daily Worker article by VG "Is this the answer to a tenant prayer.", 1955; 61103 (Box 3, Folder 48)
    - Newspaper article by VG in the Worker, includes notes, 1953-1958; 61102 (Box 3, Folder 49)
    - Notes on Daily Worker articles, 1956-1959; 61101 (Box 3, Folder 50)
    - Correspondence: Ben Levine, " Daily Worker Unsung Hero,", 1976; 61100 (Box 3, Folder 51)
    - Daily Peoples World and Daily Worker articles by VG, 1948-1957; 61099 (Box 3, Folder 52)
    - Daily Worker Radium Story by VG, 1956-1957; 61098 (Box 3, Folder 53)
    - Articles by VG, 1956-1957; 61097 (Box 3, Folder 54)
    - Correspondence from Charles Headly to Daily Worker editor, 1957; 61096 (Box 3, Folder 55)
    - Articles by VG while at Chicago Tribune, Federated Press, and Daily Worker, 1930-1957; 61095 (Box 3, Folder 56)
    - Correspondence to editor, Party Voice, Party Affairs,and Daily Worker, 1958; 61094 (Box 3, Folder 57)
    - Newspaper articles by VG in the Worker, 1959; 61093 (Box 3, Folder 58)
    - Correspondence regarding VG's article in Science and Society, undated; 61092 (Box 3, Folder 59)
    - Newspaper article by VG on "Cotton Picking,", undated; 61091 (Box 3, Folder 60)
    - Newspaper article by VG on "Cotton Picking," John Rankin, Congressman, undated; 61090 (Box 3, Folder 61)
    - Correspondence: From VG regarding employment status at an Unidentified newspaper, undated; 61089 (Box 3, Folder 62)
    - Notes and rewrite of story by VG on, "Veteran Telegrapher", undated; 61088 (Box 3, Folder 63)
    - Press Release regarding Talk Show by VG, undated; 61087 (Box 3, Folder 64)
    - Speeches by VG, 1949; 61086 (Box 3, Folder 65)
- Series V: Correspondence Addendum, 61072
  Series V: Correspondence Addendum. Consists of correspondence from the 1970s and 1980s.
  - Correspondence - to be integrated, undated; 61083 (Box 3, Folder 66)
  - Correspondence - to be integrated, undated; 61082 (Box 3, Folder 67)
  - Correspondence, 1969-1971; 61081 (Box 3, Folder 68)
  - Correspondence, 1972-1975; 61080 (Box 3, Folder 69)
  - Correspondence, 1977; 61079 (Box 3, Folder 70)
  - Correspondence, 1978; 61078 (Box 3, Folder 71)
  - Correspondence, 1979; 61077 (Box 3, Folder 72)
  - Correspondence, 1980; 61076 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1981-1982; 61075 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1983; 61074 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1984; 61073 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Series VI: Research, 60819
  Series VI: Research Files. The files for Friend and Lover consists of Gardner's extensive and unusually rich research files for her biography of Louise Bryant. Contents include clippings, correspondence and interviews with prominent friends and associates, ephemera, primary source documents including a copy of Bryant's marriage license (to John Reed), and a typescript of the book. The Rosenberg Story Research Files contain clippings and other ephemera.
  - Subseries VI:A: Friend and Lover (Research Files, Typescript), 60827
    - Appendix, undated; 61071 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Book outline, undated; 61070 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Book party invite, undated; 61069 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Book proposal, undated; 61068 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Caption material, undated; 61067 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Chapter 2, undated; 61066 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Chapter 4, undated; 61065 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Chapter 5, undated; 61064 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Chapter 6, undated; 61063 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Chapter 7, undated; 61062 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Chapter 8, undated; 61061 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Chapter 10, undated; 61060 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Chapter 11, undated; 61059 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Chapter 12, undated; 61058 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Chapter 12 - research, undated; 61057 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Chapter 13, undated; 61056 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Chapter 14; Chapter 14 - Portland newspaper clippings, undated; 61055 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Chapter 15, undated; 61054 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Chapter 15 - research, undated; 61053 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Chapter 16, undated; 61052 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Chapter 18 - research, undated; 61051 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Chapter 21, undated; 61050 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Chapter 25, undated; 61049 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Copyright, undated; 61048 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Corrigenda, undated; 61047 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Epilogue, undated; 61046 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Memos (misc.), undated; 61045 (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - B. Research Files, undated; 61044 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Abbot, Berenice, undated; 61043 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Aiken, Conrad, undated; 61042 (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Alexander, Doris, undated; 61041 (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Anderson, Sherwood, undated; 61040 (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Andreychin, George, undated; 61039 (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - Anthony, Katherine, undated; 61038 (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - Ashleigh, Charles, undated; 61037 (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - Baldwin, Roger, undated; 61036 (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - Barnes, Djuna; Oct. 1971, undated; 61035 (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - Barnett, Ernesta (Bullitt), 1972-1973; 61034 (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - Bavid, Peggy, undated; 61033 (Box 4, Folder 43)
    - Belden, Harry, undated; 61032 (Box 4, Folder 44)
    - Bell Syndicate, undated; 61031 (Box 4, Folder 45)
    - Berkman, Alexander to Louise Bryant, undated; 61030 (Box 4, Folder 46)
    - Biddle, George, 1969-1973; 61029 (Box 4, Folder 47)
    - Boardman, Robinson to Louise Bryant, undated; 61028 (Box 4, Folder 48)
    - Bohlen, Charles, undated; 61027 (Box 4, Folder 49)
    - Bome, Margaret, undated; 61026 (Box 4, Folder 50)
    - Boni, Albert, undated; 61025 (Box 4, Folder 51)
    - Bonus March, undated; 61024 (Box 4, Folder 52)
    - Boulton, Agnes, undated; 61023 (Box 4, Folder 53)
    - Bowers, Claude, undated; 61022 (Box 4, Folder 54)
    - Boyer, William, undated; 61021 (Box 4, Folder 55)
    - Boyle, Kay, undated; 61020 (Box 4, Folder 56)
    - Bradley, Ruth interviewed by Julia Ruuttila; May-1970, undated; 61019 (Box 4, Folder 57)
    - Brown, Susan Jenkins, undated; 61018 (Box 4, Folder 58)
    - Brest-Litovsk, peace of, undated; 61017 (Box 4, Folder 59)
    - Bryant Floyd Sherman, undated; 61016 (Box 4, Folder 60)
    - Bryant, Louise - 1922 series, undated; 61015 (Box 4, Folder 61)
    - Bryant, Louise - bibliography, undated; 61014 (Box 4, Folder 62)
    - Bryant, Louise "Fables for Proletarian Children," (The Revolutionary Age, Jan 25, p. 6), 1919; 61013 (Box 4, Folder 63)
    - Bryant, Louise - last years, undated; 61012 (Box 4, Folder 64)
    - Bryant, Louise - Mirrors of Moscow. Reviews, undated; 61011 (Box 4, Folder 65)
    - Bryant, Louise - newspaper clippings, undated; 61010 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Bryant, Louise - obituaries, undated; 61009 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Bryant, Louise - Six Months in Russia. Reviews, undated; 61008 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Bryant, Louise - speeches, undated; 61007 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Bryant, Louise to William Bullitt, undated; 61006 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Bryant, Louise to Anne Dennis Bursch, undated; 61005 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Bryant, Louise to Claude McKay, undated; 61004 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Bryant, Louise to John Reed in hospital, undated; 61003 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Bryant/Reed marriage certificate, undated; 61002 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Bryant, Sheridan L., undated; 61001 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Bullitt, Anne, undated; 61000 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Bullitt, Orville, undated; 60999 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Bullitt, William C., undated; 60998 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - California background 1800s, undated; 60997 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Cameron, Angus, undated; 60996 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Campbell, Marguerite interview; 27-Aug-1970, undated; 60995 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Cannell, Kathleen, undated; 60994 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Cannon, Myra L. interviewed by Juliaa Ruuttila, 1970/1977; 60993 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Carroll, Frances interviewed by Juliaa Ruuttila; Jun/Jul 1970, undated; 60992 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Cemeteries, undated; 60991 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Chi Omega/Psi Alpha Chapter, undated; 60990 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Churchill, Allen. The Improper Bohmeian. (notes), undated; 60989 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Cole, Lester, undated; 60988 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Colum, Padriac, undated; 60987 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Cowl, Carl, undated; 60986 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Cowley, Malcom, undated; 60985 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Crichton, Linley interviewed by Virginia Gardner; Apr-1971, undated; 60984 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Dasburg, Alfred and Ann, 1975-1982; 60983 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Dasburg, Andrew, undated; 60982 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Dasburg, Mabel, undated; 60981 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Day, Dorothy, undated; 60980 (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Day, Dorothy. On Pilgrimage (typescript, 34pp.), undated; 60979 (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - Dee, Ivan, 1973-1982; 60978 (Box 5, Folder data_value_missing_5e907ce4a192d285c6337ab9b8450ba4)
    - d'Anunzio, Gabriele, undated; 60977 (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - Dell, Floyd, undated; 60976 (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - Dietrich, Christopher, undated; 60975 (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - Draper, Theodore, undated; 60974 (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - Drinker Bower, Catherine, undated; 60973 (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - Drinnon, Richard, undated; 60972 (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - Dubrow, Elridge, interviewed by Virginia Gardner, undated; 60971 (Box 5, Folder 40)
    - Duncan, Isadora, undated; 60970 (Box 5, Folder 41)
    - Dunn, Robert W., undated; 60969 (Box 5, Folder 42)
    - Dyer, Madelin, interview, undated; 60968 (Box 5, Folder 43)
    - Eastman, Max, undated; 60967 (Box 5, Folder 44)
    - Ehrgott, Albert, undated; 60966 (Box 5, Folder 45)
    - Elwyn, Frances interviewed by Virginia Gardner, undated; 60965 (Box 5, Folder 46)
    - Emancipation of women and the revolution, undated; 60964 (Box 5, Folder 47)
    - Equi, Marie, 1970, 1971; 60963 (Box 5, Folder 48)
    - Eudey, Elizabeth, undated; 60962 (Box 5, Folder 49)
    - Failing, Henrietta interviewed by Julia Ruuttila; Dec-1970, undated; 60961 (Box 5, Folder 50)
    - Everest, Wesley, undated; 60960 (Box 5, Folder 51)
    - Feldenheimer (sculpture); May-1970, undated; 60959 (Box 5, Folder 52)
    - Fenton, Lela Goddard; Apr-1970, undated; 60958 (Box 5, Folder 53)
    - Finger, Avram, undated; 60956 (Box 5, Folder 54)
    - Finnish comrades to Louise Bryant, undated; 60955 (Box 5, Folder 55)
    - Fischer, Louis, undated; 60954 (Box 5, Folder 56)
    - Flanner, Janet, undated; 60953 (Box 5, Folder 57)
    - Flick/Say families, undated; 60952 (Box 5, Folder 58)
    - Frasier, Brownell D., undated; 60951 (Box 5, Folder 59)
    - Freud, Anna, 1973; 60950 (Box 5, Folder 60)
    - Gardner, Virginia, "John Reed and Lenin: some Insights based on Mss. Collection at Harvard", (Science and Society, 388-403); Fall 1967, undated; 60949 (Box 5, Folder 61)
    - George, Juillette, undated; 60948 (Box 5, Folder 62)
    - Gold, Michael, undated; 60947 (Box 5, Folder 63)
    - Goldman, Emma, undated; 60946 (Box 5, Folder 64)
    - Gorki, Maxim, undated; 60945 (Box 5, Folder 65)
    - Greene, Bill, undated; 60944 (Box 5, Folder 66)
    - Groton map, undated; 60943 (Box 5, Folder 67)
    - Hair, Mozelle interview, undated; 60942 (Box 5, Folder 68)
    - Hamblet, Millie Hunewill, undated; 60941 (Box 5, Folder 69)
    - Hartwell, Mortimer Mrs., undated; 60940 (Box 5, Folder 70)
    - Hicks, Granville, undated; 60939 (Box 5, Folder 71)
    - Hovey, Tamara Gold, undated; 60938 (Box 5, Folder 72)
    - Hug, George Mrs. interviewed by Juliaa Ruuttila; Jun-1970, undated; 60937 (Box 5, Folder 73)
    - Hunkins, Hallinan Hazal, undated; 60936 (Box 5, Folder 74)
    - Interviews, undated; 60935 (Box 5, Folder 75)
    - Irving, Leila (Borchers), interviewed by Juliaa Ruuttila, 1970; 60934 (Box 5, Folder 76)
    - Jenkins, Mrs. Frank and Olive Vinton, interviewed by Juliaa Ruuttila; Jun/Jul 1970, undated; 60933 (Box 5, Folder 77)
    - Judson, W. to Louise Bryant, undated; 60932 (Box 5, Folder 78)
    - Kemal Pasha, undated; 60931 (Box 5, Folder 79)
    - Kern, Grace interview, undated; 60930 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Kogan, Herman, undated; 60929 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Kollontai, Alexandra, undated; 60928 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Krupskaya, N. interviewed by Louise Bryant, undated; 60927 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Kuntz, Charles, undated; 60926 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Lahey, Edwin, undated; 60925 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Lamont, Charles, undated; 60924 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Larkin, Jim case - trial and sentence, covered by Louise Bryant, undated; 60923 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Lenin research notes, undated; 60922 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Luhan, Mabel Dodge, undated; 60921 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Macmickle, Emilie Muhr interview; Jun/Jul 1970, undated; 60920 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Maguire, Molly, undated; 60919 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Mack, Theresa (Tessa); Jun-1970, undated; 60918 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Marx quotes, undated; 60917 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Masses, Trial, the, undated; 60916 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - McCay, Claude, undated; 60915 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Meeropol, Elli and Beth, undated; 60914 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Meyendorff, Sasha, undated; 60913 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Miners/Labor, 1912; 60912 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Mohan, Hugh J., undated; 60911 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Mohan, Louisa, undated; 60910 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Moore, Lucia, undated; 60909 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Mussolini - Louise Bryant on, undated; 60908 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Myers, Ethel Barnard and Horton Nicholas, undated; 60907 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Nevada, University of, undated; 60906 (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Nizer - correspondence, undated; 60905 (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - Nizer - court documents, undated; 60904 (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - Nizer - court documents, undated; 60903 (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - Nizer - lists of comparison, undated; 60902 (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - Nizer - newspaper clippings, undated; 60901 (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - Oliphant, Elizabeth interview; May-1970, 60899 (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - Oregon first families, undated; 60898 (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - Overman Committee hearing, undated; 60897 (Box 6, Folder 33)
    - Parker, Margaret; Feb-1971, undated; 60896 (Box 6, Folder 34)
    - Parsons, Elsie Clews, undated; 60895 (Box 6, Folder 35)
    - Parsons, Geoffrey, undated; 60894 (Box 6, Folder 36)
    - Pearce, Charles, 1969; 60893 (Box 6, Folder 37)
    - Portland, OR, undated; 60892 (Box 6, Folder 38)
    - Portland, OR - John Reed Centennial, undated; 60891 (Box 6, Folder 39)
    - Portland newspaper on Bryant-Bullitt marriage, undated; 60890 (Box 6, Folder 40)
    - Powell, Alice, undated; 60889 (Box 6, Folder 41)
    - Powers, Alfred; Nov-1970, undated; 60888 (Box 6, Folder 42)
    - Provincetown interviews, undated; 60887 (Box 6, Folder 43)
    - Putnam, Sam, undated; 60886 (Box 6, Folder 44)
    - Psychological approach to Bullitt - notes on conversation, undated; 60885 (Box 6, Folder 45)
    - Rabinowitz Foundatioin, undated; 60884 (Box 6, Folder 46)
    - Ramp, Floyd interview, undated; 60883 (Box 6, Folder 47)
    - Reds Virginia Gardner on the film, undated; 60882 (Box 6, Folder 48)
    - Reed, John - copies of transcript, undated; 60881 (Box 6, Folder 49)
    - Reed, John - death, undated; 60880 (Box 6, Folder 50)
    - Reed, John - family, undated; 60879 (Box 6, Folder 51)
    - Reed, John in Harvard, undated; 60878 (Box 6, Folder 52)
    - Reed, John - newspaper clippings, undated; 60877 (Box 6, Folder 53)
    - Reed, John - photographs, undated; 60876 (Box 6, Folder 54)
    - Reed, John - poems, undated; 60875 (Box 6, Folder 55)
    - Reed, John to Louise Bryant, undated; 60874 (Box 6, Folder 56)
    - Reed, John to Louise Bryant, 1917; 60873 (Box 6, Folder 57)
    - Reed, John to Louise Bryant, 1920; 60872 (Box 6, Folder 58)
    - Reed, John - letters to and from Louise Bryant in Paris, undated; 60871 (Box 6, Folder 59)
    - Reed, John to Steffens, undated; 60870 (Box 7, Folder 60)
    - Reed, Margaret, undated; 60869 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Reed, Margaret to Louise Bryant, undated; 60868 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Reed, Margaret to John Reed after Louise's departure (speaking tour?), undated; 60867 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Reed Memorial meeting, 1921; 60866 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Research notes misc., undated; 60865 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Richmond, Al, undated; 60864 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Riverwood House (Paul and Louise), undated; 60863 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Robins, Raymond, undated; 60862 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Rogers, Bobby to Louise Bryant, undated; 60861 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Rosenstone, Robert, 1970-1976; 60860 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Root case correspondence, undated; 60859 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Russia misc., undated; 60858 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Russian revolution, undated; 60857 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Ruuttila, Juliaa Kathleen, 1970; 60856 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Ruuttila, Juliaa Kathleen, 1971-1974; 60855 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - San Martin, Nancy, undated; 60854 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Sanger, Margaret (Godman), undated; 60853 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Seldes, George, undated; 60852 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Sheaffer, Louis, undated; 60851 (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Sheean, Vincent, undated; 60850 (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Shirer, William L., undated; 60849 (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - Smith Miller, Leslie interview; Jul-1970, undated; 60848 (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - Steffens, Lincoln, undated; 60847 (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - Stoller, Leo, undated; 60846 (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - Stone, Judy, undated; 60845 (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - Suffrage, Oregon, undated; 60844 (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - Strong, Anna Louise, undated; 60843 (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - Thomas, Mura Dehn, undated; 60842 (Box 7, Folder 28)
    - Trask, Williard R., undated; 60841 (Box 7, Folder 29)
    - Trotzky, Leon, undated; 60840 (Box 7, Folder 30)
    - Trullinger, Louise, undated; 60839 (Box 7, Folder 31)
    - Trullinger, Paul, undated; 60838 (Box 7, Folder 32)
    - Velodarsky- Civil War, undated; 60837 (Box 7, Folder 33)
    - Voice of Labor notes, undated; 60836 (Box 7, Folder 34)
    - Walsh, Frank, undated; 60835 (Box 7, Folder 35)
    - Washburne, Claude, undated; 60834 (Box 7, Folder 36)
    - William, Albert Rhys. Legionnaire (typescript, 19 pp.), undated; 60833 (Box 7, Folder 37)
    - William, Albert Rhys. Journey into Revolution, 1917-1918 notes, undated; 60832 (Box 7, Folder 38)
    - Winter, Ella, 1971, 1973; 60831 (Box 7, Folder 39)
    - Wood, Sara Bard Field, undated; 60830 (Box 7, Folder 40)
    - Wood, Erskine, 1970; 60829 (Box 7, Folder 41)
    - Zinoviev, undated; 60828 (Box 7, Folder 42)
  - Subseries VI:B: The Rosenberg Story (Research Files), 60820
    - National Committee to Reopen the Rosenberg Case, 1985-1988; 60826 (Box 7, Folder 43)
    - Sobell-case newspaper clippings, undated; 60825 (Box 7, Folder 44)
    - Rosenberg sons, articles about, 1958; 60824 (Box 7, Folder 45)
    - Rosenberg case - newspaper clippings (unsorted), 1953-1956, 1966; 60823 (Box 7, Folder 46)
    - Reuben, William A., To Secure Justice in the Rosenberg Case (pamphlet, 31 pp.); ca., ca.1951; 60822 (Box 7, Folder 47)
    - Pamphlet: An appeal to President Dwight D. Eisenhower to spare the lives of Julius and Ethel Rosenberg, ca.1953; 60821 (Box 7, Folder 48)
    - Pamphlet: The Cold-War Murder: The Frame-up Against Ethel and Julius Rosenberg, Richard Boyer, 1951; 478720 (Box 7, Folder 49)
- Series VII: Unprocessed Materials, 437656
  - Unprocessed Materials, 437657 (Box 11)
  - Unprocessed Materials, 437658 (Box 8, Box 9, Box 10)
- Series VIII: Photographs, circa 1913-1983; 496886 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  Series VII: Photographs includes photographs of Virginia Gardner from the late 1930s and the early 1980s. Also included in this series are photographs of Robert Dunn, Andrew Dasburg, and Louise Bryant from the early 1910s through late 1950s.